<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[https://www.winnovia.co]]></title><description><![CDATA[We’re experts in more than technology. We’re experts in business, and your business model.]]></description><link>https://www.winnovia.co/blog</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2024 14:37:38 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.winnovia.co/blog-feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title><![CDATA[How do you stay on top of competitors?]]></title><description><![CDATA[Staying ahead of the competition can be a challenge, especially in today’s fast-paced business world. To ensure that your business is...]]></description><link>https://www.winnovia.co/post/how-do-you-stay-on-top-of-competitors</link><guid isPermaLink="false">63bd7659c048e2c822af36cf</guid><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2023 14:32:59 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/43eeab_58cf2260b73049a3aeac337359f00492~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>winnovia</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><br /></p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/43eeab_58cf2260b73049a3aeac337359f00492~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"></figure>
<p>Staying ahead of the competition can be a challenge, especially in today’s fast-paced business world. To ensure that your business is staying competitive, it is important to take the time to understand what your competitors are doing, and how you can differentiate yourself from them. Here are several tips for staying on top of the competition:</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>1. Analyze your value chain: A value chain is a visual representation of the flow of activities required for producing a good or service. By analyzing this chain, you can identify activities where you offer valuable advantages over competitors and fine-tune processes so that you stay competitive. Make sure to apply the same analysis to that of your competitors as well to get an understanding of their strength and weaknesses. </p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>2. Stay up-to-date on industry trends: It’s important to stay on top of any industry trends so that you don’t miss potential opportunities or new threats posed by competition. Read industry publications and blogs, participate in professional networks and conferences, and reach out to other businesses who might have insights into how certain trends might affect your industry as soon as possible </p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>3. Research emerging technologies: Technological advancements have allowed businesses across industries to gain an edge on their competition as they utilize new strategies. To stay ahead, make sure to take the time to research any emerging technologies that may help improve efficiency or provide unique benefits for customers or employees alike </p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>4. Monitor Competitors&apos; Performance &amp; Strategies: Staying aware of what your competitors are doing helps you keep track of their strategies so you can adjust yours accordingly or learn from mistakes they&apos;ve made in areas where they excel </p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>5. Connect with former clients: Keeping in touch with past customers can help give insight into market conditions and competitor activity which will enable better decision making and ahead of the curve strategies </p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>By following these tips and staying diligent in researching market conditions, evaluating strategies, networking with other individuals involved in specific industries and monitoring competitor performance will help small businesses maximize their chances at success while maintaining a competitive edge among competitors.</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[What Happened Last Week On Social Media (Marketer’s Edition)]]></title><description><![CDATA[Top 5 Updates of the Week: Elon Musk wants you to pay $8/month to keep Blue verification badges. Instagram Adds Gift sharing to Instagram...]]></description><link>https://www.winnovia.co/post/what-happened-last-week-on-social-media-marketer-s-edition</link><guid isPermaLink="false">636e5f8643255f8ce2a825b0</guid><pubDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2022 14:55:30 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/43eeab_734a8510e44145a793059b2afdcbea24~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_666,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>winnovia</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><br /></p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/43eeab_734a8510e44145a793059b2afdcbea24~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_666,al_c,q_80/file.png"></figure>
<p><br /></p>
<h6>Top 5 Updates of the Week:</h6>
<ul>
  <li><p><span style="color: #878a8c;">Elon Musk wants you to pay $8/month to keep Blue verification badges.</span></p></li>
  <li><p><span style="color: #878a8c;">Instagram Adds Gift sharing to Instagram reels, another rip off of TikTok.</span></p></li>
  <li><p><span style="color: #878a8c;">Youtube unveils online marketplace for Streaming services as a new service.</span></p></li>
  <li><p><span style="color: #878a8c;">WhatsApp launches communities, big Chat groups with up to 1,024 members allowed.</span></p></li>
  <li><p><span style="color: #878a8c;">Twitter about to turn into only fans as Elon is planning to launch paywalled content and is willing to launch a lot of monetization features.</span></p></li>
</ul>
<h6>Google:</h6>
<ul>
  <li><p><span style="color: #878a8c;">Google is getting rid of similar audience segments.</span></p></li>
  <li><p><span style="color: #878a8c;">Google introduces a new search label for Coupons &amp; Promos.</span></p></li>
  <li><p><span style="color: #878a8c;">Google introduces Ads Data hub for Marketers &amp; Advertisers.</span></p></li>
  <li><p><span style="color: #878a8c;">Google Business Profile Photo Insights are ending.</span></p></li>
  <li><p><span style="color: #878a8c;">Google rolls out two news to analyze Data in the Ads Data Hub.</span></p></li>
  <li><p><span style="color: #878a8c;">Google to end long-time messaging App “Hangouts”.</span></p></li>
</ul>
<h6>Tiktok:</h6>
<ul>
  <li><p><span style="color: #878a8c;">Tiktok updated privacy policy in EU which states Chinese companies can access user data.</span></p></li>
  <li><p><span style="color: #878a8c;">Tiktok featured officially confirmed now: The platform will inform creators about the posts you save.</span></p></li>
  <li><p><span style="color: #878a8c;">TikTok’s parent company Bytedance hints at launch of new Tiktok Music platform.</span></p></li>
  <li><p><span style="color: #878a8c;">Tiktok launches new in-app effects and events for the Native American Heritage Month.</span></p></li>
</ul>
<h6>Instagram:</h6>
<ul>
  <li><p><span style="color: #878a8c;">Instagram launches Access to selling NFTs directly in platform for selected creators.</span></p></li>
  <li><p><span style="color: #878a8c;">Instagram fixed the big causing people to lose followers, the trend was called Bots removal by IG gurus but in actual was a bug.</span></p></li>
</ul>
<h6>Meta :</h6>
<ul>
  <li><p><span style="color: #878a8c;">Meta opens Facebook’s Professional mode to all creators globally.</span></p></li>
  <li><p><span style="color: #878a8c;">Meta to ditch human-curated Facebook News stories globally.</span></p></li>
  <li><p><span style="color: #878a8c;">Meta achieves MRC accreditation for Brand Safety &amp; Quality in Ad placement.</span></p></li>
  <li><p><span style="color: #878a8c;">Meta launched Business Messaging Accelerator Program.</span></p></li>
</ul>
<h6>Twitter:</h6>
<ul>
  <li><p><span style="color: #878a8c;">Elon musk to cut around 50% of Twitter’s workforce, major tweets against employees by The New CEO.</span></p></li>
  <li><p><span style="color: #878a8c;">Twitter to shut down its slightly successful Newsletter platform “Revue”.</span></p></li>
  <li><p><span style="color: #878a8c;">Twitter pauses Crypto wallet development.</span></p></li>
  <li><p><span style="color: #878a8c;">Musk blames “Activist Groups” for the new advertising downfall.</span></p></li>
  <li><p><span style="color: #878a8c;">Twitter is up to a lot of changes, these were the some I thought needed to be shared with you.</span></p></li>
</ul>
<h6>YouTube:</h6>
<ul>
  <li><p><span style="color: #878a8c;">Youtube is expanding YouTube search insights to more languages and also introduced a new Channel page layout.</span></p></li>
  <li><p><span style="color: #878a8c;">YouTube to allow creators to go-live together as a co-streaming feature available on Mobile Apps for now, no desktop version is planned.</span></p></li>
</ul>
<h6>Snapchat:</h6>
<ul>
  <li><p><span style="color: #878a8c;">Snapchat partnered with Amazon to launch new AR filters &amp; lenses for product try-ons.</span></p></li>
  <li><p><span style="color: #878a8c;">Snap partners with fitness app strava to allow users to share Fitness snaps.</span></p></li>
  <li><p><span style="color: #878a8c;">BigCommerce teams up with Snapchat to help US merchants to integrate their shops within the app.</span></p></li>
</ul>
<h6>LinkedIn:</h6>
<ul>
  <li><p><span style="color: #878a8c;">LinkedIn working on verified Information feature along and adding “Account Creation” Dates listing on your profile.</span></p></li>
</ul>
<h6>Marketing:</h6>
<ul>
  <li><p><span style="color: #878a8c;">Apple is offering new Ad placements on Today Tab and Product pages.</span></p></li>
  <li><p><span style="color: #878a8c;">Microsoft credit Card Ads are now available globally + 11 new product updates from Microsoft.</span></p></li>
  <li><p><span style="color: #878a8c;">Patreon now allows you to host your premium video content directly within the platform.</span></p></li>
  <li><p><span style="color: #878a8c;">This week Netflix’s Ad supported tier was launched and didn’t made a hype.</span></p></li>
  <li><p><span style="color: #878a8c;">Twitch’s guest star feature is now available around the globe.</span></p></li>
  <li><p><span style="color: #878a8c;">Substack launched discussion feature to encourage in-platform engagement.</span></p></li>
  <li><p><span style="color: #878a8c;">Signal to roll out Snapchat like stories feature.</span></p></li>
  <li><p><span style="color: #878a8c;">Microsoft Ads Performance Tool upgraded with new campaign settings ans much more.</span></p></li>
  <li><p><span style="color: #878a8c;">Apple is working on building an Ad network around its sport deal with Major League soccer.</span></p></li>
</ul>
<p><span style="color: #878a8c;">source: </span>https://www.jaskaransaini.com/</p>
<p><br /></p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Delivering successful ERP Project ]]></title><description><![CDATA[A case study of Electronics Related Products Manufacturing Company. In fact, a lot of ERP projects fail mainly due to mismanagement or...]]></description><link>https://www.winnovia.co/post/delivering-successful-erp-project</link><guid isPermaLink="false">62962196735c8f5951a2a842</guid><pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2022 14:26:22 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/43eeab_3967d87b59b7407fa757941a898cac15~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>winnovia</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A case study of Electronics Related Products Manufacturing Company.</p>
<hr>
<p>In fact, a lot of ERP projects fail mainly due to mismanagement or lack of clarity on the objectives of the project. </p>
<p>Here, we are going to cover the most important elements to make your project successful. Firstly, We will explain what objectives are and also how they can help you with designing your implementation plan. This will help you a lot to make your project successful.</p>
<hr>
<p><br /></p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/43eeab_3967d87b59b7407fa757941a898cac15~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"></figure>
<p><br /></p>
<p><strong>Project Goal</strong></p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>“We are using ERP project to be a catalyst for business transformation in our Company and to establish as one of the top 5 electronics manufacturing companies in the world.”</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p><strong>Customer Background</strong></p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>“Our Manufacturing Company is a leading manufacturer of electronics related products. Our success has been established in over the last 10 years with a focus on quality products and superior service and support. In the last 5 years we have seen a steady growth in our turnover and volume.”</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>“We have invested heavily in our state-of-the-art facilities and manpower in order to maintain the status quo and achieve the objective of our strategic plan. Our objective is to expand our brand in electronics market and become the best electronics manufacturer in region.”</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>“Despite all the investment, our product range, productivity and service quality are yet to reach its full potential. The high potential growth is still untapped and we need to find a way to accelerate the business growth with minimal internal resources, in particular the human resource. Our management is aware of this fact and hence is looking to invest in human resources to develop the next generation of our products and achieve the business growth. We are looking for an ERP vendor who can help us in developing our technology, quality and business strategy.”</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p><strong>Project Objectives</strong></p>
<p>Achieving your ERP project goals is not easy. In <u><a href="https://www.winnovia.co" target="_blank">WINNOVIA</a></u>, As an ERP software vendor, you have to live with the constant pain and discomfort of change management – a long term challenge to get ERP project to success. This is because, it is not the technology project that will ensure ERP success, but it is the way in which ERP project is delivered, implemented and used to fulfill customer objectives that drives ERP success.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p><strong>What you need to remember is to focus on how the ERP solution is being used to benefit your customer’s business and make the ERP system work best for business needs.</strong> The ERP solution does not have to be perfect, and you will not be able to deliver an ERP solution that has 100% functionality all the time. You need to learn to live with the pain and discomfort of change management to get the best out of your ERP project.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>Before you start any ERP project, you need to have an agreed ERP plan with your stakeholders. <strong>This is a key ERP success factor</strong>. You also need to plan what changes in the ERP project need to be made for your business needs, and what changes in the ERP project you do not want to make because they are considered to be critical for customer’s business.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>All your key stakeholders need to agree on what they want from the ERP project. You cannot have stakeholders who say they are not interested in getting their business goals fulfilled by the ERP project. That is unacceptable and a failure of an ERP project. For example, if your stakeholder is an engineer then you cannot have a stakeholder say ‘I am not interested in seeing a product in the market that I have developed.’ That is not fair, and what you are asking for is unacceptable. This is where your stakeholder needs to understand that ERP project is about the business and its return, not the ERP software.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>To deliver an ERP project successfully, you need to understand the ERP project goal is the driver for all the changes to be made to the ERP project. The ERP project goal is what drives your stakeholders to ensure the ERP project is delivering results that will help them get what they want from the ERP project, and what they do not want from the ERP project is being avoided. For example, a stakeholder who is working on an engineering design or process may want a new part for his or her business process, and in such cases the ERP project vendor needs to make sure a new part is developed with the existing parts, and to ensure all parts, functions, documents and files in the ERP project are in sync with the engineering design and process. If you do not have an ERP project vendor who is clear and clear on this, you will not be able to deliver an ERP project successfully.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>The ERP project vendor needs to understand clearly what the stakeholders’ objectives and the change management process are. This is what you need to focus on in the early stages of an ERP project. The ERP project vendor needs to understand the need to deliver a product that will benefit your stakeholders in getting their objectives fulfilled. The ERP vendor needs to have detailed and specific requirements for the ERP project, in particular the ERP project is needed to be delivered in less than 3 years, and needs to be delivered before your next planned business plan and strategic plan. The ERP vendor needs to understand clearly the value of the ERP project. To do this, you need to have an independent consultant to understand your ERP solution and your business needs, and also your ERP vendor needs to understand clearly the key stakeholders, business rules, and business logic that you will need to develop into the ERP system.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>For all ERP project stakeholders you need to put all your focus and attention on the ERP project goals. This is your ERP project and you need to live with the pain and discomfort of change management. It is the return of your ERP project that will determine if you are a success or not. The more your ERP project will deliver, and the more your stakeholders will benefit from the ERP project, the more you will be rewarded with good ERP project results. If your ERP project is delivering 100% benefits to your stakeholders and you are getting the benefits of your ERP project, then your ERP project will deliver a return on your investment. All ERP vendors must understand this clearly.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p><strong>How to Deliver the Project Objectives?</strong></p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>Now that you have understood what are the objectives and what should be delivered, it’s time to create a detailed project plan. The project plan should include both short and long-term objectives. Short-term objectives are related to the first couple of days and the project scope. Long-term objectives are related to the project’s life.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>A detailed project plan can be defined with the help of the following:</p>
<ul>
  <li><p>Target time frame – The amount of time (in days) that the project will be completed.</p></li>
  <li><p>Start date and end date – The date when project will start and when project will end.</p></li>
  <li><p>Date of each milestone – The date when each milestone will be achieved.</p></li>
  <li><p>Milestones – A milestone is an intermediate milestone in the project.</p></li>
  <li><p>Scope of project – The scope of the project.</p></li>
  <li><p>Goals – Each goal will be a specific objective in the project.</p></li>
</ul>
<p><br /></p>
<p><strong>Conclusion</strong></p>
<p>As a business owner, you need to put all your focus on finding the right ERP vendor who has the knowledge and experience to deliver the ERP project you want. An ERP vendor does not deliver ERP project by themselves. That is why you need to make sure you are working with the right ERP vendor, which is the best one that is capable and competent enough to deliver the ERP project you want. You also need to be flexible enough and be able to communicate effectively to ensure all stakeholders fully understand and are confident that you are working with the right ERP vendor, and the ERP vendor is also clear and clear with your stakeholders on what he or she will be delivering for the ERP project.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>There is no magic recipe for ERP project success. An ERP project will not always work. You need to be realistic, and know that some of the key stakeholders will not fully understand and be confident that the ERP solution will work. They will always be on the lookout for an ERP vendor that will deliver a working ERP solution, and in a cost effective way. For example, there is no ERP vendor in the world that has a 100% success rate. So ERP vendors need to understand clearly what their success rate is, and what is their percentage of delivering an ERP solution.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>If your ERP vendor cannot deliver what you want, and they cannot deliver the ERP project you want, what they will do is to make a big promise that they will deliver the ERP solution for you, but in reality that is all they are going to do is to tell you how great the ERP software is. The best ERP vendor will deliver the ERP project you want to deliver and will meet your stakeholder’s objectives. All you need to do is to communicate with them and negotiate on your ERP project goals.</p>
<p><br /></p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Reasons for ERP projects failure      and How to Avoid Them?]]></title><description><![CDATA[ A poorly designed and implemented ERP system can cripple a business.]]></description><link>https://www.winnovia.co/post/reasons-for-erp-projects-failure-and-how-to-avoid-them</link><guid isPermaLink="false">6294ed536dfd461d9e12e2c1</guid><pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 16:22:24 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/43eeab_146795677abf4a1b88e01ac4e4753c7b~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>winnovia</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>An ERP implementation can make or break an organization. </p>
<p><br /></p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/43eeab_146795677abf4a1b88e01ac4e4753c7b~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"title="https://www.freepik.com/vectors/business-loss"alt="In WINNOVIA, We can help you make the ERP software in a way that it suits your needs, and add value to your organization in terms of the productivity, cost saving and time to market."></figure>
<p><br /></p>
<p>On one hand, a properly implemented ERP system can reduce operational and administration costs by automating many manual processes. On the other, a poorly designed and implemented system can cripple a business.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>While ERP implementations can be complex, there are usually a few main reasons they fail so often. </p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>And that brings us to the million-dollar question</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>Why do ERP Implementations Fail?</p>
<p>The ERP Implementation fails because of internal resistance, misaligned expectations, poor process implementation, incompetent stakeholders, unaccounted supporting tools, and vaguely drafted training and digital adoption programs.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>How to avoid such reasons?</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>1. Internal Resistance</p>
<p>“You cannot escape from your history. You cannot delete your history; you cannot obliterate your history. The only thing you can do is to change your history” -Dalai Lama</p>
<p>A successful ERP implementation happens when stakeholders of the company (including the people, processes, technology, and cultural aspect of the company) align and agree to the new system. This takes time and patience, but it must be done for all stakeholders to work effectively together.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>So, some ERP implementations fail due to internal resistance. The other reasons are: </p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>2. Lack of proper leadership (“If you do not have the right leaders, you have no chance to make a revolution”) </p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>3. Incompetent C-level executives </p>
<p>This happens when senior executives of the company try to steer their organizations using legacy ERP software. This is because the existing organization culture was not built on top of a modern ERP, yet the C-level executives want to change this. This can cause an internal resistance.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>4. The lack of ERP implementation teams</p>
<p>If an organization has not dedicated the time and the energy to implement the ERP, it will lack ERP expertise. For example, there may be only one ERP expert in the organization. This is a situation similar to when the organization&apos;s technology team has no one who can build its websites or apps. These teams will not be able to handle multiple large ERP implementations. This lack of ERP expertise will cause the ERP implementation to fail.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>5. Unaccounted supporting tools</p>
<p>Some ERP implementations fail when the supporting tools are not taken into consideration. For example, a customer service representative that uses a CRM software to manage the sales orders needs the ERP software to support the sales orders. He cannot manage both the CRM software and the ERP software. As a result, he cannot provide effective service. This does not mean that an ERP implementation is failed. It means that the company needs to support its users with CRM software and ERP software.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>6. Incompetent Stakeholders</p>
<p>This happens when executives, managers, team members, and functional managers are not committed to the ERP. As a result, they do not follow the ERP, thus causing an implementation to fail. They may ask for features to be added that the company does not have in the ERP software. This causes a failure.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>7. Poor Process Implementation</p>
<p>If a company has not defined processes in the new ERP software, a failed implementation happens. The reason is that the entire new organization culture is not clear and defined. Without clearly defined processes, the new ERP software may not be used properly. In fact, some ERP implementations fail because of a lack of a defined implementation plan.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>8. misaligned expectations</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>The ERP vendor and the business owner often have different goals, which can become a major problem during the implementation process.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>It is very easy to understand what is necessary to make a business enterprise function smoothly and efficiently. But it is a different story to define what you really want, what you are expecting from an ERP implementation.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>This is a challenging and complex process because the goals of the user, the internal staff and the vendors, should all be taken into consideration.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>It is important to note that not all organizations have the same needs or want the same things. For example, when one organization is looking for a more simple and streamlined ERP implementation, it can be difficult to convince the owner and the stakeholders that such an implementation is not a good fit.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>Business is complex and it is not just a matter of installing the system, but involves a set of processes, tasks and steps. It is for this reason that a business needs to choose an ERP partner that can help in managing all these aspects. We are business consulting firm and we know how to implement business management software for companies of all sizes. Whether the requirement is for a basic upgrade to an ERP or a complete new software solution, our team of ERP experts will ensure that you get the desired results.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>In <u><a href="https://www.winnovia.co/" target="_blank">WINNOVIA</a></u>, We can help you make the ERP software in a way that it suits your needs, and add value to your organization in terms of the productivity, cost saving and time to market. We can also ensure that your new or replacement software is built to meet the business requirements. We ensure that the implementation is completed successfully and on time.</p>
<p><br /></p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Different Approaches to Digitalization]]></title><description><![CDATA[Today, it is becoming a major competitive advantage for businesses to manage their resources  more effectively and efficiently. So, Is...]]></description><link>https://www.winnovia.co/post/different-approaches-to-digitalization</link><guid isPermaLink="false">616ac65daeec7c001613cea7</guid><pubDate>Sat, 16 Oct 2021 12:43:20 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/43eeab_5f03c367b122413a8b02ca4218091e53~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>winnovia</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><br /></p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/43eeab_5f03c367b122413a8b02ca4218091e53~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"></figure>
<p><br /></p>
<p>Today, it is becoming a major competitive advantage for businesses to manage their resources  more effectively and efficiently. </p>
<p>  </p>
<p>So, Is Enterprise Resource Planning implementation is a digital transformation?</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>A:</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>Yes, it is.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<h6>Enterprise Resource Planning versus digital transformation  </h6>
<p><br /></p>
<p>We have a lot of discussions about Enterprise Resource Planning (ERP) versus digitalization. In fact, I’ve been thinking about this debate for the last year or so and here’s why I‘ve started to think about it more. I think there’re two different approaches to digitalization that need to be addressed.  </p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>The first is enterprise resource planning, which is about the management of data through the use of software and databases. This includes things like accounting, payroll, inventory, billing, sales, and financial management. The second is digitalization, which involves the use and development of tools for managing all forms of information and activities related to organizations. The two approaches are very different. Enterprise Resource planning attempts to manage a business’ operations through the development of data management applications and the use thereof. Digitalization is about creating tools that allow companies to manage information without the need for an application.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>So, it’s important to know that there is a significant difference between “digital  transition” and “Digital Transformation.” The distinction is not as clear as one might perceive, particularly on a software development level.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>In general, a digital transition is not a technology transformation. It is a digital (and, in many cases, more so) organizational transformation. To put this differently, a technology transition is a process or a technology that is “transforming” to a new level, while a digital or organizational transformation is a level of organization that has been changed. This distinction is important for the reason that it is often a good idea to treat digital and organizational changes as separate and distinct phases.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>An example of this is that the software development process, in particular, is often considered a technology, but not an organizational or digital transformation. In order to be successful, it may be necessary to consider a few additional factors in the development of the software.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>For example, many software developers are focused on testing the software as it is developed. They may also consider the cost, the schedule, and the quality of the development process in order to determine whether to implement or to leave it as is. In addition, it will often be necessary for the software developer to consider the business impact of the change, and also to consider whether the change is likely to be disruptive or whether it will be incremental.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>This is an important distinction to keep in mind. In some cases, it can be very helpful to consider these additional factors, especially when making decisions about the development and deployment of software. For example, it could be that the business is not going to adopt the new software, but they will adopt the old software. This may help to identify an opportunity for the business to use the new version as a backup or replacement. Or, it might be that it may not be necessary or that the new system is not designed to work with the old system.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>The focus on the costs of development can be helpful, but it can also be counterproductive. When a business is facing a new technology or a new business environment, it should try to adopt as many parts of the system as possible, regardless of cost. If the business does not adopt those parts of a system, they can still be used, but will be less efficient and more costly.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>It is also important to consider other factors that will affect the business in the future. These include the introduction of new technology, changes to the business model, and new competitors. These factors can all be addressed by considering what is needed to adapt to these changes and by taking into account the business’ goals in the process.</p>
<p>So, it goes without saying that all of these factors should be considered when making a decision about the software that will be used.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>Another important distinction is that in many of the cases where the business will face a digital change, it also is important that the technology is changing in a way that allows it to be adopted without significant disruption to the current business. For this reason, it often is best to consider digital transformation as a software-specific transition, rather than an organizational transformation as such.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>A further important distinction, which is not often considered, is that digital transformation is often used to refer to the creation of an innovative organizational structure or of business models, while digital transformation can also refer to change in business processes.</p>
<p>Organizational transformation is used to describe the change of business processes, not the change in the organization itself.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>Here are the many ways in which digital, organizational, and digital transformation are used interchangeably and differentiated:</p>
<p>• Digital transformation describes the change from an existing “old system” (in this case, the old business) to a “new system“ (in other words, a new organization and/or new business).</p>
<p>• Organizational transformation describes a change from “traditional” business processes to “innovative” or “unconventional” processes. This means that the organization has changed, but the processes that are used to govern the processes have not changed.</p>
<p>• The term digital transformation describes change in an organization for the purpose of creating a new system and/ or business model.</p>
<p>These terms are used throughout this document in a loose sense, that is, they may be used to mean different things, and different aspects of the same thing.</p>
<p>To be clear, I am not trying to define digital transformation, but rather to use this term to describe a digital organizational change. I am also not saying that digital, or digital and/organizational, changes are synonymous. Instead, I use the terms to describe two different types of changes: digital and digital and to describe different aspects or aspects of this change.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>Further, I do not use the term digital to refer only to a change in technology, or in the type of technology that will take place. In many cases it will refer to a digital process that will occur instead of a technology change, such as the use of a new application programming interface (API) or the addition of a database in a new database.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>However, there are other cases where digital transformation refers to both technology and a change to an organization. In these cases, the technology changes but the organization does not.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>Let me illustrate with a couple of examples. One is the use that some businesses make of their existing systems and processes, such that they are no longer tied to a set of specific processes. For instance, a company might use a different set of processes to run its business, but still have some common business processes that it uses across its business.</p>
<p>When the company makes this type of change, the company can be said to be transforming from an old system to a newer one.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>On the other hand, another type of digital transformation includes the use, for example, of a particular business model or architecture, rather that the use a new set of software or a different type of software altogether.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>There are many examples of this type in the world today, but I will focus on two just for the sake of clarity.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>One is the IBM Watson “Cloud” platform for business. This is a cloud-based software platform that can be used on the IBM Cloud’ for business, which runs on IBM’ s private and public clouds.</p>
<p>At the heart of this platform is business analytics and business process modeling software called Watson, which enables business users to build and run business analytics, business process models, and business rules.</p>
<p>IBM built a cloud platform for Watson called Watson Cloud Analytics, which allows the company to deploy Watson software on IBM Cloud. It can also access IBM Cloud using virtual machines, which can be created by a third party.</p>
<p>Through this cloud platform, IBM is creating a software platform for enterprises to use to build new applications, such a cloud service.</p>
<p>I am not an expert on IBM products, but there are many organizations that use IBM products on their own private clouds, which are not part of IBM”s cloud service, and to which the IBM cloud service has no access.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>While the Watson platform is a good example of the use and deployment that can occur on the “other side of the fence” of a digital, digital and, organizational transformation, the IBM platform does not represent a ‘digital transformation.’</p>
<p>The IBM platform is not intended to represent a business transformation. Instead it is an innovation in business analytics that, in a sense, is a business model change. It does not allow for the use or deployment of new business processes or models.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>Thus, the use IBM Watson’ cloud platform on IBM cloud is not equivalent to the use the IBM software on the company’ private cloud. IBM Cloud is a different platform than the IBM private cloud, and it is not the same as the IBM service. However, I believe that it represents a digital and a digital- and organizational-transformation.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p><strong>Next, I will show how organizations can use both types of digital and organizational transformations.</strong></p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>Some types of organizational transformation are more likely to occur in organizations than others. In general, organizations will more likely experience a digital transformational change than a digital reorganizational change. For organizations to experience either an organizational change or a digital re-organizational change, they are likely to need to adapt, and this can require a lot of adaptation.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>As an example, let’ say that an organization is about to implement a new process that is not an enterprise resource planning (ERP) process, such the creation and implementation of a document management system. If this is done through an ERP process, it requires the adoption of a legacy system that can no longer be used in an effective manner. If it is done by implementing a document system, there is probably not much change in processes other than the adoption and use of the new document system. However this change is not digital because many of these processes are still used on a legacy ERP system. The adoption of the document system could be, for instance, the adoption or use of document management software, document classification software, and so on.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>If this process is implemented through a digital workflow, it represents an organizational digital transformation because it requires a change, at least for the implementation phase, from an enterprise software environment to software that is better suited to the new process. This change may be the application of new software or new processes. The need for a new data infrastructure may also be required to support this change in data modeling and data management.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p><br /></p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Start With Behavioral Segmentation To Build Marketing Strategy and Why That's Important?]]></title><description><![CDATA[A framework that teaches how to build a marketing strategy that is scalable to a wide range of audiences.]]></description><link>https://www.winnovia.co/post/start-with-behavioral-segmentation-to-build-marketing-strategy-and-why-that-s-important</link><guid isPermaLink="false">6165921d409372001784bef8</guid><pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2021 14:03:01 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/43eeab_8a183bce541640a387ff7c9b5f23d10b~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>winnovia</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><br /></p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/43eeab_8a183bce541640a387ff7c9b5f23d10b~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"alt="<a href='https://www.freepik.com/vectors/love'>Love vector created by pch.vector - www.freepik.com</a>"></figure>
<p><br /></p>
<h3><strong>A framework that teaches how to build a marketing strategy that is scalable to a wide range of audiences, but also a variety of different types of audiences. </strong></h3>
<p><br /></p>
<p>Before we get into the specifics of what this framework is, let&apos;s first say that the core of this </p>
<p>framework is to decide which type of audience they want to build? And What&apos;s the most </p>
<p>useful tools for marketers to create behavioral segmentation?</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p><strong>What is behavioral segmentation?</strong></p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>A lot of marketers are trained in the concept of analyzing the audience of a marketing </p>
<p>program through behavioral segmentation. </p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>Behavioral segmentation is the process of training your organization to identify, identify, and identify all the factors that make a consumer&apos;s response to a consumer&apos;s behavior very </p>
<p>different from what they would normally expect from the consumer&apos;s behavior.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p><strong>Which type of audience they want to build?</strong></p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>The most common kind of behavioral segmentation is using a &quot;situational segmentation&quot;. </p>
<p>For example, if you want to build a website about a specific health care product, you train </p>
<p>Your team to analyze the customer&apos;s reaction to each of the three different features of the </p>
<p>product.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>The &quot;situational segmentation&quot; technique can be particularly useful for large organizations, </p>
<p>because it can provide a much more general understanding of how a product or service works, and it&apos;s usually only a matter of time before you have a product or service that is on the market.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p><strong>What&apos;s the most useful tools for marketers to build behavioral segmentation?</strong></p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>Behavioral segmentation is a very powerful tool when it comes to building marketing strategy.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>It&apos;s really pretty easy to use.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>If you have a lot of time, money, and experience, and you have an understanding of the </p>
<p>process of segmentation, you can start building a very efficient marketing strategy.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>When you start to build a product or service that is scalable to your target audience, you can build a lot of new value that helps you grow your brand, or get more customers on your homepage.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>If you have a lot of experience and are able to implement a lot of tactics, and are able to target a broad range of audiences, then you can start to build the marketing strategy that&apos;s really relevant to your target audience.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>This means that you can have a very specific strategy that you can scale to your target market. The main point here is that you should be able to build a very flexible marketing strategy that will work for varying different audiences, and to target different types of audiences.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p><strong>What are the main reasons you want to build a marketing strategy?</strong></p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>The main reason that you want to build a marketing strategy is that you want to build a marketing strategy that is scalable to your target audience, and that can scale to different audience types.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p><strong>To build a marketing strategy that works for different audiences, you need:</strong></p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>A strong strategic plan to build a marketing strategy that works for different audiences.</p>
<p>The ability to adapt to different needs of your target audience.</p>
<p>The ability to target different types of audiences.</p>
<p>A strong understanding of how the marketing strategy works.</p>
<p>A strong ability to understand the process of segmentation.</p>
<p>You can leverage these different types of factors, but they are mostly just the ones that will get you a successful marketing strategy.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p><strong>How do I use this strategy?</strong></p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>First of all, you need to understand the process of segmentation. This is the process by which you build a marketing strategy. If you&apos;re not familiar with the process of segmentation, it&apos;s basically the process of segmentation is that you create a plan of action, which is basically a list of metrics that you want to target with a specific goal.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>For example, you can define a goal and measure your audience. Then, you can target different types of people, and then you can target different types of people by asking them questions, which you can then measure.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>You can then target different types of people by asking them out on dates, and then you can target different types of people by asking them out on dates.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>That&apos;s pretty much it.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>The process of segmentation is really useful for a lot</p>
<p><br /></p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Artificial intelligence as a marketing tool]]></title><description><![CDATA[Marketing Analytics The use of artificial intelligence in marketing has recently become one of the most popular and discussed topics. AI...]]></description><link>https://www.winnovia.co/post/artificial-intelligence-as-a-marketing-tool</link><guid isPermaLink="false">6093296dcbabd200152cae3c</guid><pubDate>Wed, 05 May 2021 23:29:48 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/43eeab_8d7b49644ab14234b9d12cf1780ebf1e~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>winnovia</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><br /></p>
<p><br /></p>
<p><br /></p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/43eeab_8d7b49644ab14234b9d12cf1780ebf1e~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"></figure>
<p style="text-align: left;"><strong>The use of artificial intelligence in marketing has recently become one of the most popular and discussed topics. AI opens up many new opportunities and prospects for marketers and business owners, and interest in this technology is only growing.</strong></p>
<p><br /></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">For a long time AI was perceived as something from the realm of science fiction or as a technology of the distant future, however today AI-based systems solve practical problems and bring real benefits to business. AI has become an indispensable marketing tool, and this is due to the changes that are happening now.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">Among many reasons for such changes, first of all, the growth in data volumes. This is a global trend driven by the increasing popularity of mobile devices and the expansion of the online business. Moreover, the significance and usefulness of AI as a tool for analyzing large volumes of information is beyond doubt.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">Another reason is the development of technology. This is directly related to the increase in data volumes: processing a large amount of information requires a more advanced and modern technological base.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">As a result of the changes that have occurred at the present stage of development of the AI ​​sphere, personalized marketing in real time has become possible. Personalization has become one of the fundamental global trends in marketing, and this is directly related to the implementation of AI technologies.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><strong>Personalized approach</strong></p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>
</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">To get a response from the target audience, ready to purchase promoted products or services, is the main goal of each marketing campaign. Based on this, approaches and measures are developed that are aimed at meeting the needs of the target group of consumers. Until recently, it looked something like this: for example, a commercial for washing powder was placed in intervals during the broadcast of the series, popular among housewives.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>
</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">But today, thanks to AI, the targeted approach has become a reality, when advertising can no longer be directed to a wide audience, but to a specific consumer, which means it becomes as effective as possible. Personalized and relevant advertising content that meets all the needs of a particular consumer, allows you to get the right response and stimulate the purchase.
</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">Personalization involves building communication with the consumer on a whole new level. In this case, all factors are taken into account: gender and age characteristics, interests and needs of the audience, the most acceptable format of communication, etc. That AI allows you to implement this approach, since each advertising message contains a number of elements that can be personalized (format, image, color palette, message, slogans, etc.). In addition, advertising can be adapted taking into account the broadcast area, the technical capabilities of the medium, time of day, season and many other factors. AI-based systems are able to instantly analyze all these conditions and provide a high level of personalization, so they are becoming an increasingly popular marketing tool.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">The use of AI as a marketing tool gives business representatives a number of advantages
</p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><strong>· Analysis and practical application of information in real time. </strong>Modern systems based on AI can not only accumulate huge amounts of information about visitors, but also systematize it and then put it into practice. They can recognize many different scenarios and instantly make decisions based on the data received;</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><strong>· In-depth knowledge of the needs of your audience</strong>. AI technologies allow you to better know the needs and interests of the target audience, evaluate the reaction of consumers to each advertising campaign and subsequently use this knowledge in the development of marketing events;</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><strong>· Optimization of advertising costs.</strong> The use of AI technologies makes it possible to optimize the budget due to a clearer understanding of the needs of the audience and a reduction in the cost of irrelevant, and therefore ineffective advertising. Thus, marketing funds will be spent more efficiently and rationally.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">Today, AI technologies are actively developing, new opportunities appear, and the functionality of systems is expanding. Therefore, the study and implementation of AI becomes an important task in the implementation of the marketing strategy.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><strong>In order for marketing to be effective, modern marketing specialists using AI to understand the impact on the results of the campaign of various factors and sources of information in real time, such as weather, season, time of day, etc. All this affects consumer behavior and is necessary to increase efficiency advertising. We must not forget that the relevant advertising, maximally tailored to the given consumer and the surrounding conditions, is perceived not as an imposition of a product or service, but as a useful assistant when making purchases, therefore it brings the best results.</strong></p>
<p><br /></p>
<p><br /></p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Fintech startups are not limited to blockchain]]></title><description><![CDATA[Fintech startups are not limited to blockchain Fintech is not limited to only such revolutionary inventions as blockchain, and in the...]]></description><link>https://www.winnovia.co/post/fintech-startups-are-not-limited-to-blockchain</link><guid isPermaLink="false">609327b3139eae001572d6d5</guid><pubDate>Wed, 05 May 2021 23:20:23 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/43eeab_8a001936f20b4f52b123d141c57ffddc~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>winnovia</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><br /></p>
<h2><span style="color: #545454;">Fintech startups are not limited to blockchain</span></h2>
<h2></h2>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/43eeab_8a001936f20b4f52b123d141c57ffddc~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"></figure>
<p><br /></p>
<p>Fintech is not limited to only such revolutionary inventions as blockchain, and in the near future we will see how financial services are transformed under the influence of technologies that everyone has been waiting for for a long time. Individual technologies appeared at different times in different places, but because of the immaturity of computing power and high cost, they did not find development. Biometrics, artificial intelligence, processing of large amounts of data, augmented reality - each direction will entail changes in the field of financial services.



- Biometrics will allow you to identify a person remotely and fill remote service channels. Fewer bank branches will be required, but more biometrics identification points. 

- Artificial intelligence will allow turning investment consulting into a mass service, which will become a cheap and instant option. 

- The use of big data processing will make mass personalization possible when an offer is delivered to the user here and now. 

- Augmented reality will provide the consultant robot with a tool to visualize the decision in a format that matches the user&apos;s preferences and habits. VIP banking will become massive and remote.



The current perception of blockchain is largely known as a disruptive technology that will break down all existing institutions based on the services of an intermediary and build ecosystems of equal participants. The three advantages of the blockchain are most often called: the absence of an intermediary (peer-to-peer, if this is an advantage at all), data integrity (due to &quot;immutability&quot; - invariance of records, &quot;golden copy&quot; - the presence of authentic data for each user, &quot;traceability&quot; - data traceability) and the ability to implement self-executing smart contracts. An example of the latest technology is a bond,



Most real blockchain projects in the financial sector (if not all projects at all) are based on two advantages - a guarantee of data integrity and the possibility of implementing smart contracts. To give up trust - the role of a mediator - is unlikely to succeed in the foreseeable future. It is needed, for example, from the point of view of guaranteeing the fulfillment of obligations, since it will take responsibility for resolving certain problem situations (defaults, hacker attacks, etc.). Therefore, now in infrastructure organizations private blockchain systems are being developed - private blockchains, where verification is carried out in one way or another by selected participants.



All these changes are a huge field for innovation and search and the very broth in which fintech companies grow and multiply. Each bank chooses how to go through these changes, but is unlikely to be able to abandon experiments.



Among the fintech <u><a href="https://www.winnovia.co/" target="_blank">startups</a></u>, there are solutions for children, banks and forensic scientists. For example, the project of the financial marketplace PandaMoney will help parents teach their child how to handle money and how to accumulate it correctly in game mode. Ozforensics recognizes photo fraud using algorithms for visualizing altered areas: it detects pixel structures indistinguishable to the human eye in different areas of the image and visualizes artificially altered areas. Startup Smart Security identifies the user by his behavioral characteristics. The solution uses a continuous machine learning cycle to authenticate based on how users naturally interact with their digital devices. An attacker will not be able to use the stolen login and password, because his manner of entering this data will be completely different from the patterns that the owner showed.



</p>
<p>


</p>
<p>
</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Sales formula every business owner must know]]></title><description><![CDATA[Sales formula every business owner must know Almost 70% of business owners do not measure anything, they just think something and that's...]]></description><link>https://www.winnovia.co/post/sales-formula-every-business-owner-must-know</link><guid isPermaLink="false">60932647627d2e0015826b82</guid><pubDate>Wed, 05 May 2021 23:16:13 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/43eeab_6370c0b123a345e3bbe16a0a99412008~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_740,h_489,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>winnovia</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><br /></p>
<p><span style="color: #545454;">Sales formula every business owner must know</span></p>
<p>
</p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/43eeab_6370c0b123a345e3bbe16a0a99412008~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_740,h_489,al_c,q_80/file.png"></figure>
<p><br /></p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><strong>Almost 70% of business owners do not measure anything, they just think something and that&apos;s it and that&apos;s enough. Enough !? This may even be enough to go bankrupt ...</strong></p>
<p><br /></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">In any business, it is important to identify key indicators. Which will give you a picture of where your business is and where it is moving. And it can move in two directions: Business is either growing or falling, there is no third.
</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">There is simply no third way in business, it wasn’t invented. You cannot stand in one place. If you stand in one place, then you are rolling down because competitors are not standing.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>To find out where you are moving, determine the necessary business growth indicators and start measuring them. Daily, weekly, monthly, quarterly, annually. Compare them with past periods. Build charts. Hang the charts in a prominent place so that they are constantly seen by all the employees responsible for the indicators.
</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">Sales are the foundation of any business. The foundation on which it stands. And if sales have faltered, then the business itself feels shaky and require special attention.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><strong>For most businesses, selling is a chaotic, random, seasonal process. And you just need to build a system out of them. With the confident work of all components. And of course, link it all on stable business processes and instructions.</strong></p>
<p><br /></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">The easiest way to increase sales is to increase each indicator in the sales formula, which is shown below:
</p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><strong>Profit = Profit Margin(M) * Sales Volume (V)</strong></p>
<p><br /></p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><strong>Sales Volume (V) = Sales Leads * Conversion Rate (Cv) * Price per transaction (P) * The number of transactions (N)</strong></p>
<p><br /></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">Sales volume (V) is all sales, the total amount of proceeds from a certain period of time. It can be a week, a day, or maybe a month, and six months and a year, etc.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">Margin (M) is what we add on top and cost. It is expressed as a percentage.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">If you know the sales volume, you get the formula: Leads multiplied by the Conversion Rate, multiplied by the average price and multiplied by the Number of Transactions.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>
</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">Where:</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">Sales Leads are the numbers of your potential customers, those customers who called you, or who found out about you, or went to your store if you have a store.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>
</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">Conversion Rate (Cv) - expressed as a percentage. This ratio shows how many percent of people you buy from all that contacted you or those that you found. The Conversion Rate formula is simple - the number of people who bought divided by Leads (by those people who found out about you) and multiplied by 100%.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>
</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">Price per transaction (P) is the average amount of money that one customer leaves at your checkout.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>The number of transactions (N) is the number of purchases made by the client from you. That is how often he buys from you.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">In 90% of businesses, you can increase the frequency of customer calls. Just think about how you can make customers buy from you more often. (For example: Change your toothbrush every 3 months. Apply shampoo to your head, rinse, apply again.)</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><strong>Everything is simple. Keep statistics on these indicators. Develop programs to increase each of them. Write down specific current values ​​and what indicators need to be achieved by which date. Post schedules of their changes to a place that is visible to everyone, especially for sales managers. And the monthly sales reports will be optimistic for you.</strong></p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>
</p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><span style="color: #b4b4b4;">Photo by Lukas from Pexels</span></p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[40 Rules for Selling]]></title><description><![CDATA[40 Rules for Selling If you ask any executive about the major challenge he would face in his business, you will hear a consistent...]]></description><link>https://www.winnovia.co/post/40-rules-for-selling</link><guid isPermaLink="false">6093253fc89b110015bcd0dd</guid><pubDate>Wed, 05 May 2021 23:10:45 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/43eeab_12fc52f4a26644ca812516e5ca7336f2~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>winnovia</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><br /></p>
<h2><span style="color: #545454;">40 Rules for Selling</span></h2>
<p><br /></p>
<h3><span style="color: #a8a8a8;"><strong>If you ask any executive about the major challenge he would face in his business, you will hear a consistent compliant: Sales!</strong></span></h3>
<p><br /></p>
<h3><span style="color: #a8a8a8;"><strong>Regardless of what you’re selling, it’s easier than most people think.  Just keep the following tips in mind…</strong></span></h3>
<p><br /></p>
<p>
</p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/43eeab_12fc52f4a26644ca812516e5ca7336f2~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"></figure>
<p>

</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">1. <strong>Call more and call now.</strong> Prospect by default, but have in mind that every time you&apos;ll try to start prospecting your brain will make up a thousand excuses to convince you it&apos;s not the best moment to do it.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">2. <strong>It&apos;s easier to sell to those who already have your product or a similar one.</strong></p>
<p><br /></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">3. <strong>Use a script.</strong> Your key message must be delivered in your first intervention and be contained in no more than 3 sentences.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">4. <strong>Desensitize yourself to rejection.</strong> Every &apos;no&apos; gets you closer to the next &quot;yes&quot;.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">5. <strong>If the receptionist doesn&apos;t like you, you&apos;ll never reach the decision-maker.</strong></p>
<p><br /></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">6. <strong>The quickest way to be liked is to ask for help.</strong></p>
<p><br /></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">7. <strong>Don&apos;t talk to non-decision makers.</strong> Be nice to them, they can become referrers, but don&apos;t talk to them about your product or company. A non-decisionmaker can&apos;t say &quot;yes&quot; but can say &quot;no&quot;.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">8. <strong>There will be objections.</strong> If it doesn&apos;t let you to move forward smoothly, It is objection. It&apos;s trivial whether the objection is based on a truth or not. &quot;Send me more information by email&quot; is also an objection.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">9. <strong>Don&apos;t believe anything.</strong> (Almost) everybody lies, about almost everything, almost all the time; and the reason why that happens is irrelevant.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">10. <strong>Don&apos;t send presentations.</strong> No one reads them, and even if they did, you&apos;d first need to figure out what your potential customer wants to know, and to figure out what your potential customer wants to know you need to have a conversation, and once you&apos;ve had a conversation a presentation is no longer needed. Potential customers only use presentations to discard candidates, never to hire them.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">11. <strong>Work your eloquence.</strong> Be brief, be concise, don&apos;t digress, stay firm, don&apos;t doubt, be interesting.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">12. <strong>Don&apos;t be generous when it comes to availability.</strong> If it&apos;s scarce it must be good.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">13. <strong>Don&apos;t plan your meetings.</strong> No matter how many scenarios you think of, and how many questions you get ready for, every meeting will develop in a different way from what you imagined.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">14. <strong>Become friends.</strong> Under same conditions people choose their friends, and under unequal circumstances… also. It doesn&apos;t matter how good your product is if the customer doesn&apos;t like you.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">15. <strong>Shut up.</strong> Don&apos;t interrupt. Don&apos;t even nod. Just shut up and pay attention. If you talk more than 20 % of the time, you are doing it wrong. If you listen before pitching, by the time is your turn the customer would have already told you everything he wants to hear.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">16. <strong>Don&apos;t move.</strong> Don&apos;t nod, don&apos;t smile, don&apos;t force your laughter. Just look and listen.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">17. <strong>Don&apos;t try to convince.</strong> Great salespeople don&apos;t try to turn &quot;no’s&quot; into &quot;yes’s&quot; -that&apos;s impossible-, what they do is to quickly detect -and reject- those who won&apos;t buy.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">18. <strong>Don&apos;t say you are good, show it.</strong> Give hints and let the customer reach the conclusions, it&apos;s way more believable.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">19. <strong>Don&apos;t talk about yourself.</strong> Your product, your company, and your life are boring. Like everyone&apos;s else. Like mine. Don&apos;t tell your client what you do, tell him how his life will be after buying whatever is you offer.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">20. <strong>Safety and ego are heavier than features and benefits.</strong> When someone buys from you, he puts his job in the line, or that&apos;s what he thinks. Once the customer is not afraid of losing his job, admiration from peers becomes sexier than the pricest treasure.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">21. <strong>Kill presentations.</strong> If you are a great speaker, a presentation will diminish your value; if you are a bad speaker, it will be even worse.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">22. <strong>Don’t sell.</strong> Contradict your client, deny some of his requests, show disinterest.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">23. <strong>Learn to say &quot;no&quot;.</strong></p>
<p><br /></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">24. <strong>Don&apos;t be a butler.</strong> Avoid those &quot;please&quot;, &quot;thank you&quot;, and &quot;excuse me&quot; that you wouldn&apos;t genuinely say to a friend. While you are at it, kill the &quot;are you busy?&quot; and, above all, murder once and for all the denigrating &quot;thank you for your time&quot;.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">25. <strong>Brag about your flaws.</strong> Start by mentioning the drawbacks of your product. Most drawbacks become advantages once you brag about them, and when not, you&apos;ll be transmitting honesty and they&apos;ll remember you for being unique.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">26. <strong>Interested customers are the least interesting.</strong> A customer showing too much interest, in hurry, or who brags about how well one is doing, doesn&apos;t want to buy anything. Think of it, when you are about to buy something expensive, do you want the seller to know you are willing to do anything to get it?</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">27. <strong>Best way of solving objections is silence.</strong> Second best, whatever that starts with &quot;That&apos;s exactly why&quot;.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">28. <strong>Do not solve objections.</strong> What the customer asks is not what he wants to be answered to. Behind every objection hides laziness or lack of trust. To overcome the former there&apos;s nothing to do but insisting; to overcome the latter, the customer must like you. If you answer to what you are asked, you&apos;ll lose your chance to do either and the conversation will end.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">29. <strong>Ask &quot;why&quot; times fives.</strong> Soon, you&apos;ll find that what your potential customer wants is not exactly what he first said.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">30. <strong>After every interaction </strong><em><strong>you</strong></em><strong> say what the next step is.</strong></p>
<p><br /></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">31. <strong>Keep emails below 100 words and containing no more than one goal or question.</strong></p>
<p><br /></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">32. <strong>Always-fucking-deliver.</strong> Be punctual, and if you agree on something, do your part exactly when and how you agreed.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">33. <strong>Don&apos;t customize your proposals.</strong> And keep them under 3 pages. Whenever you deliver a proposal you are delivering free work. The more free work a client feels you have given him, the less he&apos;ll value you.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">34. <strong>Be Persistent.</strong></p>
<p><br /></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">35. <strong>If in doubt, phone.</strong> I also prefer the email, but email is for cowards, and cowards can&apos;t sell.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">36. <strong>Ask for the close.</strong></p>
<p><br /></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">37. <strong>Network everywhere, with everyone, all the time.</strong> Go to events and introduce yourself to others, but leave twitter and those events in which everyone already know everyone. This is about making money, not about being popular among peers and competitors.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">38. <strong>Get your contacts to introduce you to their contacts.</strong> This will help your sales more than everything I said before.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">39. <strong>Almost-sales don&apos;t generate revenue.</strong> That&apos;s why you&apos;ll never say again that a client is hot or that a deal is almost closed.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">40. <strong>There&apos;s no sale until you get paid.</strong> The deal is not closed when a client says he wants to work with you. Not even when he signs the contract. Only a deal is closed when someone else&apos;s money gets into your company&apos;s bank account.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p><br /></p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[What is the difference between sales forecast and demand forecast?]]></title><description><![CDATA[Demand Forecasting and Sales Forecasting are different, and the results of each can have a dramatic impact on your profitability. There’s...]]></description><link>https://www.winnovia.co/post/what-is-the-difference-between-sales-forecast-and-demand-forecast</link><guid isPermaLink="false">6093219987b56f0015e50c16</guid><pubDate>Wed, 05 May 2021 23:05:18 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/43eeab_f47255f54b1a456c9fa99fcee4acac12~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>winnovia</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><br /></p>
<p>Demand Forecasting and Sales Forecasting are different, and the results of each can have a dramatic impact on your profitability.</p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/43eeab_f47255f54b1a456c9fa99fcee4acac12~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"></figure>
<p><br /></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">There’s a misconception that demand forecasting and sales forecasting are the same. Many people think they’re interchangeable. Actually, there is a big difference that will lead to drastically different accuracy results; even though sales and demand forecasting use both, similar and different data points, to calculate the forecast.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p style="text-align: left;"> </p>
<p><br /></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">Sales forecasting is generally a prediction of market response and relies on real numbers compared to experience and intuition. It uses mathematical equations and calculations to provide the company with a detailed outlook of anticipated revenue over a specific future time period (typically broken down into short, medium, and long time periods). It also helps to determine financial plans with banks, anticipate sales growth, and allocate resource strategies. Sales forecasting is based off previous revenue and sales figures.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">It&apos;s simply a guess of how much we will sell this coming year based on:</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">i) Experience. We sold 100 units last year with 4 salespeople, we hired one more salesperson so we forecast sales of 125 units next year.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p style="text-align: left;"> </p>
<p><br /></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">ii) Intuition. It’s a startup but everyone is going to want one of our products and there are 100 million people and we expect to 80% would purchase our product so we forecast to sell just about 80 million. </p>
<p><br /></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">As you can see, Sales Forecast can vary widely depending on what you choose to input.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">One form of sales forecasting is micro forecasting. This focuses in to give the business a hard revenue target and determine the market share of a specific product. It then anticipates the market share of that product and how it will adapt over time - shown in the form of a percentage of total sales that product receives in relation to sales revenues of its competitors in a specific market segment.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p style="text-align: left;"> </p>
<p><br /></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">Demand forecasting relies rather heavily on the economic and consumer conditions in the market place. While it is a type of sales forecasting, its goal is different. It attempts to determine the consumer interest for a product across the entire market place. Essentially, demand forecasting provides critical data about the markets a company currently operates in, and those it hopes to move in to. Without demand forecasting, the business assumes the risk of pursuing and operating in a market that potentially doesn’t have a need for their product.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p style="text-align: left;"> </p>
<p><br /></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">Demand forecasting gauges the current level of demand for a specific product or service and projects how that demand will shape the future demand curve. It requires accurate current and previous market, sales, and revenue numbers to predict future demand. Without those figures, it becomes much more challenging to make accurate projections, though not impossible.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p style="text-align: left;"> </p>
<p><br /></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">This type of forecasting is often used in the short term because of the rapid and unforeseen factors that affect and influence demand over time. It is also used more heavily in inventory replenishment.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p style="text-align: left;"> </p>
<p><br /></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">For example, for a retailer to forecast the demand in June, it would need to know:</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">i) How much we sold last May vs. what we sold this May?</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">ii) Annual trend (up 2% or down 5% - whatever)</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">iii) Sales Orders already in place for June</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">iv) How many Sales Orders we had in place this time last June?</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">v) What is current inventory position?</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">vi) What is current manufacturing/purchasing capacity?</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">So, the demand forecast is going to use an algorithm to weight and combine all these variables (and probably several more) to project what to buy or make in order to insure we have enough product on hand to meet our demand.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">And if you’re Demand Forecast goes wrong, you either end up with too much inventory, which self-corrects the July Demand Forecast or you run out of product, which should bump up the July Demand Forecast so it doesn’t happen again.</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Dynamic Pricing]]></title><description><![CDATA[While it is not an entirely new concept and companies have been using it randomly over the years, dynamic pricing is much more relevant...]]></description><link>https://www.winnovia.co/post/dynamic-pricing</link><guid isPermaLink="false">608dcd9a3df26d0057745019</guid><pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2021 22:00:38 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/43eeab_e7e643b2abf748d19541f25825000203~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>winnovia</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><br /></p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/43eeab_e7e643b2abf748d19541f25825000203~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"></figure>
<p><br /></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">While it is not an entirely new concept and companies have been using it randomly over the years, dynamic <strong>pricing</strong> is much more relevant in the new age of e-commerce companies. Simply put, <strong>dynamic</strong> pricing is a <strong>strategy</strong> in which <strong>product</strong> prices continuously adjust, sometimes in a matter of minutes, in response to real-time supply and demand.  </p>
<p style="text-align: left;"> </p>
<p style="text-align: left;">For example, if you own an e-commerce company, you should seriously consider adopting this pricing model, since it has several benefits for your business. Rather than being overwhelmed by this fast-paced pricing dilemma, e-commerce stores like Amazon have used dynamic pricing to their advantage by adjusting their prices at the same rapid pace of market demand.                         </p>
<p style="text-align: left;"> </p>
<p style="text-align: left;">A common argument against dynamic pricing is that it reduces your control over your products&apos; prices. As a retailer using dynamic pricing, you&apos;ll have access to real-time price trends across thousands of products in your industry.                                </p>
<p style="text-align: left;"> </p>
<p style="text-align: left;">Actually, many e-commerce retailers shy away from dynamic pricing because of the potential damage to their brand value and user experience. However, Amazon dominated the market by using dynamic pricing strategies that go beyond human capabilities. Since Amazon&apos;s pricing engine makes millions of price changes in a day, of course, some customers noticed and complained about this price discrimination strategy.             </p>
<p style="text-align: left;">
</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">In essence, dynamic pricing is the concept of selling the same product at different prices based on the changing dynamics of the current market demand. This pricing strategy benefits from high demand at certain times of the year. The penetration pricing model is often used when a new business enters the market, or an existing business wants to dominate the market. After businesses reach a certain amount of customer base and demand, they gradually increase prices.                                                                                                                </p>
<p style="text-align: left;">Also, you can use dynamic pricing to launch seasonal and promotional offers as well, while remaining profitable.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">
</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">If you&apos;re considering adopting a dynamic pricing strategy and tools, feel free to schedule a free call with our experts. <a href="https://www.winnovia.co" target="_blank">WINNOVIA</a></p>
<p><br /></p>
<p><br /></p>
<p><br /></p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Build Reliable Sales Estimates During the Pandemic]]></title><description><![CDATA[For more effective forecasting, businesses need to examine how the pandemic has changed customer demand, habits and expectations.]]></description><link>https://www.winnovia.co/post/build-reliable-sales-estimates-during-the-pandemic</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5fa40b1484b3e7001788720f</guid><pubDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2020 14:47:12 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/43eeab_51e63417801f46d2841525baa2646a46~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>winnovia</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="color: #333333;">Monte-Carlo simulation as a technique for modeling demand</span></p>
<p><br /></p>
<p><br /></p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/43eeab_51e63417801f46d2841525baa2646a46~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"></figure>
<p><br /></p>
<p><span style="color: #333333;">In this article, we will give an overview of the practical application of Monte Carlo simulations to build a sales forecast model. We will describe how to create a Monte-Carlo simulation to predict the probability distribution of a sales forecast for a particular product or service in a particular market. In </span><u><a href="https://www.winnovia.co" target="_blank"><span style="color: #333333;">WINNOVA</span></a></u><span style="color: #333333;">, we use Monte Carlo simulation where we calculate the probability of a sale on each simulated day and run the simulation thousands of times. The result is a probability distribution of all possible outcomes, so we have to do it hundreds of thousands of times! If we analyze the Monte-Carlo simulations, the resulting probability distribution resembles a normal distribution.</span></p>
<p> </p>
<p><span style="color: #333333;">When it comes to forecasting, rather than simply replacing uncertain variables with a single average, Monte Carlo simulation may prove to be a better solution, especially if we use multiple values. Monte-Carlo simulations calculate scenarios based on the definition of simulation parameters. They use the selected distribution and its parameters, automatically generate thousands of scenario iterations, usually in just a few seconds, and then use them in a series of iterations. </span></p>
<p> </p>
<p><span style="color: #333333;">You can run them in a series of iterations, changing the underlying parameters used to simulate the data. You can also perform multiple iterations of the same scenario with different parameters to change their use for simulating data, and then perform them again in different scenarios without changing them. Monte-Carlo simulations show that each variable contributes to a particular outcome of the model. Monte Carlo simulations allow analysts to see exactly which input factors have values for certain results. They allow you to specify the variables and the relationship between them, and then use them to predict future sales of a particular product or service. Monte-Carlo simulation allows you to simulate dice to get more accurate predictions. It can help you to mimic combinations of variables in the real world and give you a reliable probability of the results of these combinations. In such situations, it can be applied to analyze the effects of randomness introduced into the model by such variables.</span></p>
<p><br /></p>
<p> </p>
<p><span style="color: #333333;"><strong>Conclusion</strong></span></p>
<p> </p>
<p>The past few months certainly haven’t been easy for businesses. Many had to shut their doors due to the <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/coronavirus/" target="_blank"><span style="color: textColor0;">coronavirus pandemic</span></a>. While some may never reopen, others are ramping up their business — and hoping they don’t have to shut down again. This needs rapidly validating models, creating new data sets, and enhancing modeling techniques. Getting this right will enable companies to successfully navigate demand forecasting, asset management, and coping with new volumes. </p>
<p> </p>
<p>For more effective forecasting, businesses need to examine how the pandemic has changed customer demand, habits and expectations, and how it has affected market supply of materials, goods and services. Which industries are thriving and which are suffering? Which businesses will either temporarily or permanently change how they operate and are there any that have gone away permanently? All these factors will affect staffing, financing and other management decisions, so it is vital to have access to up-to-date, pertinent data in order to achieve more reliable forecasting results.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p><br /></p>
<p><br /></p>
<p> </p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Power of Mathematical Modeling in Business Decision Making]]></title><description><![CDATA[One of the most common misconceptions among businesspeople is that there isn't a scientific way to analyze and solve business problems. ]]></description><link>https://www.winnovia.co/post/the-power-of-mathematical-modeling-in-business-decision-making</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5f9fb0eb302ca30017199c66</guid><pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2020 07:19:55 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/43eeab_83d67db2d2e348b9b4fa635a3003cf28~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_720,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>winnovia</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><br /></p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/43eeab_83d67db2d2e348b9b4fa635a3003cf28~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_720,al_c,q_80/file.png"></figure>
<p><br /></p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>On the contrary, Analysts can model difficult practical problems and offer insights into their potential impact on corporate decisions. In addition to the decisions about the operation of a particular business, many other factors play a role in decision-making. The constraints associated with budget, investment, and organizational considerations can make the decision-making process even more difficult for business.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>To model complex systems, analyze the trade-offs between the most important system variables, identify robust solutions, and develop decision-support tools, operations research requires the use of mathematics to identify and analyze complex problems as they are expressed in everyday language, as well as to analyze trade-offs in key systems and variables, and to develop decisions and support tools. Mathematics is used in decision-making primarily in a language called mathematical modeling, in which we discuss the parts of a decision problem that can be described in numbers, similar to relationships or in sequence. Mathematical models can describe complicated decision-making problems, including those that affect the interactions between their components. </p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>Mathematical modelling uses mathematics as the language in which we describe it and as a tool to dictate and control the decision-making process. The process of looking at a decision problem is a process in itself, not a set of concepts or rules that were invented for this purpose only. Mathematical modelling is therefore a language in its own right, not a concept or rule invented for this very purpose, as in the case of the rule of thumb. </p>
<p>The main objective of mathematical modelling of this process is to make the decision - to make the process more efficient, effective and transparent. One of the most important things that can be modelled with mathematical and statistical methods is the ability to select and use appropriate mathematics and statistics to analyze and better understand empirical situations and improve decisions. </p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>When creating a mathematical model, the technology is able to vary assumptions, investigate consequences and compare predictions with data. The model can help explain the system, study the effects of different components and make predictions about behavior. </p>
<p>Mathematical models can take many forms, including mathematical equations, mathematical models, computer models and mathematical algorithms. Although a particular model includes a variety of abstract structures, other models may overlap in some ways. </p>
<p> </p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Why Companies need to calculate Customer Lifetime Value?]]></title><description><![CDATA[In previous article, we discussed how startups can use ARPU to add value to SaaS application?. We concluded that even that ARPPU (Average...]]></description><link>https://www.winnovia.co/post/why-companies-need-to-calculate-customer-lifetime-value</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5f97fe4db1f4f3001754dcdd</guid><pubDate>Tue, 27 Oct 2020 11:07:54 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/43eeab_1610c3d8cca24151921b3776bc719091~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_740,h_493,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>winnovia</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="color: #545454;"><span style="background-color: #ffffff;">In previous article, we discussed </span></span><u><a href="https://www.winnovia.co/post/using-apru-metric-to-add-value-to-saas-applications" target="_blank">how startups can use ARPU to add value to SaaS application?</a></u><span style="color: #545454;"><span style="background-color: #ffffff;">. We concluded that even that ARPPU (Average Revenue Per Paying User) grows, but Paying Share falls, this will lead to a reduction in your income - the profit from paying will not be able to compensate for the reduction in their number. This metric helps you evaluate and predict your income. Today, we will discuss why they need to calculate Customer Lifetime Value (CLV or LTV)? and how they can use it for their benefit?</span></span></p>
<p><br /></p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/43eeab_1610c3d8cca24151921b3776bc719091~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_740,h_493,al_c,q_80/file.png"></figure>
<p>Customer lifetime value (CLV or LTV) - the sum of all the profit that the customer has brought or will bring to the company for the entire time of cooperation with her. It allows you to determine how much your customers spend, how often and how long they buy from you.</p>
<p>This metric refers to a long-term customer service strategy.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>How to calculate customer lifetime value</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>Let&apos;s look at several calculation methods:
</p>
<p><strong>Option 1</strong></p>
<p><strong>LTV = [Profit] - [CPC]</strong></p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>where CPC is the cost per customer acquisition.
</p>
<p>We will not consider the calculation of the cost of one client (lead). For many, this is obvious, and modern analytical tools allow you to do this automatically for each channel of attraction, and choose the most effective.
</p>
<p><strong>Option # 2</strong></p>
<p>We take the average values ​​for all indicators.</p>
<p><strong>LTV = [Average bill] x [Number of sales] x [Period of cooperation]</strong>
</p>
<p>For example:</p>
<p>($25 per sale) x (12 sales per year) x (2 years) = $600 .</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>LTV goal: Optimization of the marketing budget for customer acquisition. Based on the obtained values, we can increase the costs of attraction by linking them to all profits from the client, and not to profit from the first sale.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>As you might have guessed, LTV calculation is based on internal analytics of your company, and not data common to the market.
</p>
<p><strong>Customer retention rate</strong></p>
<p>Another important indicator is the customer retention rate (CRR). It supplements the data on the customer’s lifetime value and allows you to analyze the effectiveness of the selected marketing strategy.</p>
<p>Simplified formula for calculating customer retention rates:</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p><strong>CRR = ((E * N) / S) * 100</strong></p>
<p>E - the number of customers at the end of the period;</p>
<p>N - the number of new customers attracted for the period;</p>
<p>S - the number of customers at the beginning of the period.
</p>
<p>Example: Take a specific customer segment. At the beginning of the year there were 450 customers [ S ]. Over the course of the year, it took 100, but we attracted 150 new [ N ]. Those. At the end of the year we have 500 customers [ E ]. Based on the above formula, we obtain:
</p>
<p>((500-150) / 450) * 100 = 77.7%
</p>
<p>It will also be useful to calculate the coefficient of outflow (turnover) of customers (Churn rate). When a customer stops buying from you.
</p>
<p>Simplified formula:</p>
<p>(10 clients left / 160 clients) * 100 = 6.25%</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p><strong>Why do companies need LTV?</strong></p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>The calculation of the customer’s lifetime value shows which customers are more or less valuable in monetary terms.</p>
<p>When developing a strategy for attracting customers, we can calculate the cost of attracting one customer based not on the profit from one (usually the first) sale, but on the profit from all sales to the client. Thus, we can increase the cost of attraction, which will pay off in the long run.
</p>
<p><strong>How to increase customer lifetime value?</strong>
</p>
<p>A lot of factors influence the increase of this indicator, but let&apos;s look at some of them:
</p>
<p>For example, you can determine the LTV for different segments of your customers and, based on the data received, increase or decrease the cost of attracting specific groups of customers. Therefore, to attract segments of more loyal customers and increase revenue from each client and the total revenue of the company.
</p>
<p>Constantly analyze the problems and needs of your customers. Based on this analysis, create and offer new products and services. Even if they are not typical for you at this stage of your company’s development. Be a &quot;single point of entry&quot; for customers to solve their daily problems.
</p>
<p><br /></p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Using APRU metric to add value to SaaS applications]]></title><description><![CDATA[Any business create metrics with one goal - to increase profits. However, as Seth Godin rightly remarked: “The metric can be accurate and...]]></description><link>https://www.winnovia.co/post/using-apru-metric-to-add-value-to-saas-applications</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5f97fd67e58c560017b08879</guid><pubDate>Tue, 27 Oct 2020 11:01:42 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/43eeab_6a17f7381f44406982cdf8976c35f723~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_740,h_493,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>winnovia</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Any business create metrics with one goal - to increase profits. However, as Seth Godin rightly remarked: “The metric can be accurate and consistent with the goals of the company, but working on it is completely pointless if it is not related to what you came to work for today.”</p>
<p>
 </p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/43eeab_6a17f7381f44406982cdf8976c35f723~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_740,h_493,al_c,q_80/file.png"></figure>
<p>With this approach, the ARPU indicator can be a useful metric as it combines both components - income and value. 


<strong>ARPU</strong> (Average Revenue Per User) - the average income that you receive from each active user for the period . This metric helps companies measure product value, forecast profits, and make decisions based on these numbers. 


<strong>How to calculate ARPU?</strong>
So, to calculate the average income from a user for a month, you need to divide the total income for this month by the number of users who were active during this period.




Let&apos;s say this month 600 people have used your service (we consider everyone: those who have been using the free trial period, those who have been with you for 5 years, those who have subscribed to the most expensive tariff - now we are talking about everyone who like or use the service for a month). Revenue amounted to $3200. It turns out that your ARPU this month amounted to: 3200/600 = $5.3




<strong>Which ARPU is good?</strong>
We got the result, but how to interpret it? 5.3 is good or bad? The fact is that ARPU does not have an optimal value. But there is one rule: if ARPU is reduced, you need to attract more customers.


This metric cannot be specifically estimated because it is very much related to the number of customers. For example, consider two companies with two similar services (when comparing two ARPUs, you must take necessarily close companies or products).
Analysts of both services calculated ARPU, and in both cases it amounted to $15. Only now, Service1 in first company  was used by 700 people this month (100 people used the free trial period), and the income was $9000. At Service2 in second company, things were not going so well - only 300 customers were recorded (and also 100 people at a free tariff), income was $ 4,500. It turns out that equal ARPUs for equal companies with equal desired income do not mean the same thing.


You can evaluate ARPU only within your business, or compare it with the result of a company that boasts a similar (in terms of characteristics and volume) audience. 


<strong>For what period to consider the ARPU indicator?</strong>
First you need to decide what period you are interested in. Reading ARPU once a month is especially convenient for services that work by subscription. However, if the average user lifetime (average Lifetime) for your company is small (as, for example, in mobile applications), it makes sense to calculate ARPU more often.


Strictly speaking, the ARPU for the month is correctly called ARPMAU (Average revenue per monthly active user).


If the Lifetime of users of your service is small, it is better to consider ARPDAU (Average revenue per daily active user) - the average income from an active user per day.


If you do not work by subscription, pay attention to how often customers need your services. 


To assess the quality of traffic, you can calculate the income from users who came to you in a certain period (for example, everyone who registered on June 15). To do this, consider cumulative ARPU. The formula is similar, but it calculates the income that a particular group of users brought to you. Every day, the ARPU for this group will increase, which is why it is called cumulative.


Cumulative ARPU (X days) = (Revenue from the selected group for X days / Number of users within this group)


For example, on June 15, 800 people registered in your service. On the same day, they paid a total of $600. ARPU in this case will be (600/800 = $0.75)


Suppose the next day this group brought you $300. Even if some of the users who arrived yesterday left you or did not use the service on the second day, the size of the group remains the same - 800 people. Cumulative ARPU for 2 days will be (600 + 300) / 800 = $1.125. Every day he will continue to grow.


You can consider Cumulative ARPU for 1 day, week or 2 weeks - this way you will find out how much money each client brings for the first time you work with you, and you can also predict what income and after what time it will bring.


With an increase in the period, this indicator increases and gradually reaches the level of your CLV (Customer Lifetime Value).


<strong>How is ARPU related to value?</strong>
At the very beginning, we said that ARPU links income and value. This may seem strange: is it just about money?


In fact, ARPU shows how much the user is willing to pay for your product. Suppose you offer 3 tariff plans and a free trial period. A monthly subscription for each of the paid tariffs costs $15, $20 and $30 respectively. You counted ARPU and it was $ 23. If we take into account that we take into account users of the trial period who do not pay anything, it turns out that most of your payers prefer expensive tariffs


And if most of the users choose the most expensive tariff plan, it is likely that they are willing to pay more. If you do not offer them this opportunity, you are losing money. 


High ARPU shows that users value your product. Therefore, when the indicator reaches the value of your average (at a price) tariff, you can safely raise prices. 


If ARPU is approaching the cost of the cheapest tariff, it&apos;s time to work on marketing. You attract people who pay a little, it makes sense to slightly change the strategy and attract the attention of users to more expensive tariffs. 


<strong>How ARPU and CLV are related?</strong>
Many would confuse these two metrics and sometimes ignore ARPU metrics and consider only CLV (because they think that it is almost the same thing). They are really connected, but each is important individually. 


CLV is the profit that the client brings to you for the entire time you work with him. ARPU shows the profit from your work with the user for a certain period. The difference between these metrics is Lifetime - the life expectancy of the client within your company. 




CLV shows the total customer value for your company, and ARPU shows the current state of business relation.


<strong>What is the difference between ARPU and ARPPU?</strong>
One letter here really matters a lot, because the extra P in ARPPU is Paying. ARPU shows the average income for all users, even those who have not paid anything this month. ARPPU is revenue per paying user. There are always fewer payers, so this indicator is always higher.


ARPPU will show you the reaction of paying users to product value.


However, if you raise prices, your ARPPU will also increase, but this is not a reason to celebrate. Perhaps the share of paying customers has fallen, it’s just that prices have become higher, so the figure has risen. 


It is the share of paying customers (Paying Share) that links ARPU and ARPPU. 




For example, this month you had 1,200 users, 40 of them paid for premium access. The income was $1000. 


ARPU = 1000/1200 = $ 0.8


ARPPU = 1000/40 = $ 25


The proportion of paying users = 0.8 / 25 = 0.032 or 3.2%. 


The optimal amount of Paying Share depends on the type of business. For example, for mobile applications, an indicator of 1-2% is a good result (most use the free version, not many people make purchases in applications). 


Considering the proportion of paying customers is important. The fact is that if ARPPU grows, but Paying Share falls, this will lead to a reduction in your income - the profit from paying will not be able to compensate for the reduction in their number. This metric helps you evaluate and predict your income.


<strong>How to use ARPU metric in marketing?</strong>
ARPU shows how the value of your product relates to its value. 
How else can I use this metric?


<strong>1- Compare yourself with competitors.</strong>
It is this metric that investors are interested in when they decide which company to invest in. If within the framework of your business you launch two or more projects, you can determine the most effective one also with the help of ARPU: whoever has a higher indicator, he won.


Important! You can compare ARPUs only of companies (products) with the same or related audience.


<strong>2- Measure reaction to price changes.</strong>
Suppose you decide to raise the cost of a monthly subscription and see if ARPU changes for new users (the one with you for less than a month). Last month, you recorded 810 newcomers, and the income was $ 900. After the introduction of the new price, the number of users decreased to 700, revenue - up to $800. To evaluate the result of a price increase, compare ARPU.


ARPU before upgrade = 900/810 = $ 1.11


ARPU after upgrade = 800/700 = $ 1.14


It turns out that the experiment is quite successful, and the reduction in income is not associated with an increase in price. If at the same price to attract more active users, the income will increase.


<strong>3- The choice of channels of attraction.</strong>
CLV is often used to evaluate the effectiveness of the acquisition channel, but ARPU is also great for this. Suppose you had 2,200 customers this month, they brought you $ 4,000. It turns out that your ARPU = 4000/2200 = $ 1.81.


You have launched a new advertising campaign, and now you have 3450 users and $ 5000 of revenue. Sounds great, but look at the numbers:


ARPU = 5000/3450 = $ 1.44


It turns out that the income has decreased - it seems that you have attracted not quite the target audience.


<strong>4- User segmentation.</strong>
You can divide all users, for example, according to the time of subscription start date, and compare the profit from each group. Let&apos;s try to identify 3 groups: beginners (those who came to you less than a month ago: they use a free trial period or paid for a subscription for the first time), those who are already familiar with you (prolonged a monthly subscription already 2-3 times), and regular customers ( renewed the subscription more than 3 times).


It turns out that the main income you bring are from those who have long been with you, and newcomers. By focusing on these two groups, you can significantly increase profits.


<em>Important! The user may not have made a payment in a specific period for which we consider ARPU.</em>


<strong>5- Forecast for the future.</strong>
You can express your hypotheses in money related to attracting or retaining users using ARPU. Suppose you are launching a new advertising campaign and expect to attract 20% more new users - previously 120 people came to you every month, and after the launch you are preparing to meet 144. With an ARPU of 30, your income will be 4320 (and it was 3600). It’s very convenient to evaluate how the costs of a new campaign pay off and what income awaits you next.


<u><a href="https://www.winnovia.co/" target="_blank"><strong>How to improve this metric</strong></a></u>
Whatever your ARPU, there is no limit to perfection. In <u><a href="https://www.winnovia.co/" target="_blank">WINNOVIA</a></u>, we will analyze the most common ways to increase this metric.


In <u><a href="https://www.winnovia.co/" target="_blank">WINNOVIA</a></u>, We know how to add value to your product. The more often the customer made payments, the higher his next payment. It is very important to monitor user engagement, activation and retention - the deeper a person understands the value (and the faster he does it), the more likely that he will stay with you seriously and for a long time. This directly affects your income, which means it increases ARPU.</p>
<p>
 </p>]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>